The problem with scaling gradient descent is simple.
梯度下降的规模所带来的问题很简单
You need to compute these gradients.
你需要计算这些梯度
Here's another rule of thumb.
而另一个经验法则是
If computing your loss takes n floating point operations,
如果计算损失函数需要 n 次浮点运算
computing its gradient takes about three times that compute.
计算其梯度则大约需要 3 倍运算量
As we saw earlier,
正如我们之前看到的
this last function is huge.
最后一个函数非常庞大
It depends on every single element in your training set.
它与训练集中每一个元素都是相关的
That can be a lot of compute if your data set is big,
如果你的数据集很大 这可能需要很大的计算量
and we want to be able to train on lots of data because in practice,
我们当然希望有大量数据进行训练
on real problems, you'll always get more gains,
在实际情况中
the more data you use.
使用的数据越多越好
And because gradient descent is iterative,
因为梯度下降法是迭代算法
you have to do that for many steps.
你需要多次重复这些步骤
That means going through your data tens or hundreds of times. That's not good.
这意味着所有数据要经历几十甚至上百次计算  这并不理想
So instead, we're going to cheat.
因此我们打算采用一些取巧的办法
Instead of computing the loss,
与计算损失不同
we're going to compute an estimate of it,
我们来估计损失
a very bad estimate,
它是一个非常差的估计
a terrible estimate, in fact.
实际上它可以说是差到家了
That estimate is going to be so bad,
这个估计如此糟糕
you might wonder why it works at all.
以至于你会奇怪 究竟它为什么会起作用
And you would be right because we're going to
你也许想到了
also have to spend some time making it less terrible.
因为我们会想办法去改进它
The estimate we're going to use is simply computing
我们将使用的估计只是简单计算
the average loss for a very small random fraction of the training data.
随机选取的一小部分训练数据的平均损失
Think between one and a thousand training samples each time.
每次处理一到一千个训练样本
I say random because it's very important.
我强调随机选取 因为这一点是非常重要的
If the way you pick your samples isn't random enough,
如果你选择样本的方式不够随机
it no longer works at all.
该方法就不再奏效
So we're going to take a very small sliver of the training data,
我们选取一小部分的训练数据
compute the loss for that sample,
计算它们的损失
compute the derivative for that sample,
计算它们的导数
and pretend that that derivative is the right direction to use to do gradient descent.
并认为这个导数的方向是梯度下降的正确方向。
It is not at all the right direction.
虽然实际上它并不总是正确的方向
And, in fact, at times,
事实上 有时
it might increase the real loss, not reduce it.
它甚至可能使损失增加 而不是减少
But we're going to compensate by doing this many,
因此我们需要许多许多次这样的计算
many times, taking very,
来进行补偿
very small steps each time.
每次计算都是非常小的一步
So each step is a lot cheaper to compute,
所以每步计算的负担就减小了很多
but we pay a price.
但我们还是付出了代价
We have to take many more smaller steps instead of one large step.
我们必须进行多得多的小步骤 而不能一步到位
On balance though, we win by a lot.
总而言之 我们还是赢了
In fact, as you'll see in the assignments,
事实上 正如你将在作业中看到的那样
doing this is vastly more efficient than doing gradient decent.
这样做比逐个样本进行梯度下降更有效率
This technique is called stochastic gradient descent,
这种方法被称为随机梯度下降
and is at the core of deep learning.
它是深度学习的核心知识点
That's because stochastic gradient descent scales well with both data and model size,
这是因为随机梯度下降能够适应各种数据和模型的大小
and we want both big data and big models.
我们希望大数据和大型模型
Stochastic gradient descent, SGD for short,
随机梯度下降 简称 SGD (Stochastic Gradient Descent)
is nice and scalable.
是一种优秀的 可扩展的方法
But because it's fundamentally a pretty bad optimizer
不过 由于它本质上是一个糟糕的优化器
that happens to be the only one that's fast enough,
却又恰恰是唯一足够快的优化器
it comes with a lot of issues in.
它存在许多需要注意的问题